B. KARTHIK

SALES MANAGER



CONTACTS:

Email: -karthik2022@gmail.com

Phone:

8610057575/9710021734

Address:

no.1855, Vasantham Colony, Anna Nagar, ch-40.

LinkedIn: -

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

Karthy-b-430613187/

KEY SKILLS: -

Operation management

Strategic planning

Account management

Team leadership

Event management

Business management

Performance-oriented Sales Leader offering exceptional record of achievement over 6-year career. Tenacious manager with strategic and analytical approach to solving problems, bringing in customers and accomplishing profit targets. Talented in identifying and capitalizing on emerging market trends and revenue opportunities.

WORK HISTORY

2018-11-2023-05

SALES MANAGER in

GENIE TRANS VISION PVT LTD (sales & operation)

- → Helped sales professionals maintain customer relationships by making follow up calls to recent buyers.
- → Supported sales team with administrative assistance such as coordinating paperwork and responding to basic inquiries.
- → Monitored competitor activities and pricing strategies to compare performance.
- → Generated reports to track sales activity and performance.
- → Analysed customer feedback and identified areas for improvement.
- → Managed accounts to retain existing relationships and grow share of business.

2015-12-2018-08

DUPTY MANAGER (EVENT MANAGEMENT) in VISION HIRE (SALES & OPERATION)

- → Maintained professional, organized, and safe environment for employee and patrons.
- → Cross-trained existing employees to maximize team agility and performance.
 - → Developed and maintained relationships with customers and suppliers through account development.
 - → Controlled costs to keep business operating within budget and increase profits.
 - → Improved marketing to attract new customers and promote business.
 - → Recruited, interviewed and hired employees and implemented mentoring program to promote positive feedback and engagement

LANGUAGE: -

ENGLISH, HINDI, TAMIL: -

(Speak, write, Read)

TELUGU, MALAYALAM

(CAN UNDERSTAND)

PERSONAL DEATILS:

Nationality: Indian

Sex : Male

Marital status: Single

Work location: Ready to relocate (anywhere in India).

03-2014-10-2015

SR. SALES EXECUTIVE (INTERIOR MANAGEMENT) in PRENAKX HABITAT PVT LTD, CHENNAI.

- → Established and cultivated solid business relationships with new or existing customers.
- → Researched sales opportunities and possible leads to exceed sales goals and increase profits.
- → Achieved sales goals and service targets by cultivating and securing new customer relationships.
- → Monitored and adjusted pricing based on market trends and customer feedback to meet expectations and increase sales.
- → Created and implemented successful sales campaigns to drive leads and increase sales.
- → Negotiated and closed profitable sales contracts with new and existing customers to increase loyalty and retention.
- → Engaged in friendly conversation with customer to better uncover individual needs.

08-2008-

SR. SALES CONSULTANT (LOAD COMMERCIAL SHOWROOM) BALAJI AUTOS (MAHINDRAN & MAHINDRA).

- → Applied knowledge of market and full range of innovative and unique products to meet customer needs, expanding company's customer base.
- → Cold calling and conducted face-to-face sales meetings to reach assigned sales targets.
- → Created detailed sales presentations to communicate product features and market data.
- → Implemented up-selling strategies, encompassing recommendation of accessories and complementary purchases.
- → Followed up with existing customers to provide additional support and References
- → Evaluated customer purchase requirements and recommended best-fit to their company

11-2006-06-2008

SERVICE ADVISOR (CAR SERVICE CENTRE) LANSON TOYOTA, CHENNAI.

→ Pleasantly greeted customers and asked open-ended questions to better determine needs.

02-2014

- → Documented problems and corrective actions to maintain records.
- → Suggested add-on services that would be helpful to customers and improve bottom line.
- → Developed estimates by costing materials, supplies, and labor.
- → Informed customers of service specials, completion times, and service expenses to provide exemplary customer service.
- → Maintained high customer satisfaction standards to meet or exceed targets.

B.KARTHIK,

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

01-2018- 02-2019	MBA (INTERNATIONAL BUSSINESS ADMISTRATION) (PG) UNIVERSITY OF MADRAS-CHENNAI.
03-2002- 06-2006	B.E MECHANICAL ENGINEERING MADHA ENGINEERING COLLEGE, CHENNAI.
03-2001- 06-2002	HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL, VELANKANNI MATRIC.SCHOOL, CHENNAI.

CERTIFICATIONS

02-2001 PGDCA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 10-2004 DIPLOMA IN AUTOCAD

Declaration:-

Place: Chennai

	I hereby declared the above information's are true to my knowledge.	
Date:	Signature	